<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Alexandru Dima &#8211; jsDay 2016</title>
	<atom:link href="/speakers/alexandru-dima/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>The international Javascript Conference</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 15:18:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Shipping one of the largest Microsoft JavaScript applications (Visual Studio Code&#8217;s story)</title>
		<link>/talk/shipping-one-of-the-largest-microsoft-javascript-applications-visual-studio-codes-story/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2016 07:31:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=talk&#038;p=510</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[How can you survive a project that uses JavaScript massively and must be continuously evolved? Visual Studio Code is a cross platform code editor indistinguishable from a native editor, but its code base was not always meant to be for a desktop application. In this talk I will share the key insights that allowed us [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>How can you survive a project that uses JavaScript massively and must be continuously evolved?<br />
Visual Studio Code is a cross platform code editor indistinguishable from a native editor, but its code base was not always meant to be for a desktop application. In this talk I will share the key insights that allowed us to create a rich code editing experience and that will help you in managing a large, always evolving, JavaScript code base. We will take a deep look into the major steps in the evolution of VS Code from its humble beginning more than 4 years ago to one of the largest TypeScript code bases at more than 350k lines of TypeScript.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.w3-edge.com/products/

 Served from: 2016.jsday.it @ 2017-02-13 21:20:41 by W3 Total Cache -->